Phyllis McGinley Papers
Phyllis McGinley Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Lynes, Russell, 1965; 1973,; undated (Box 13)
    See also Harper's Magazine
  - Lyons, Barbara, 1960 (Box 13)
  - M, 5 folders (Box 13)
  - McAleer, John J., 1973-1975 (Box 13)
  - McBride, Mary Margaret, 1946-1951 (Box 13)
  - McCall's, 1930-1967 (Box 13)
  - McCarthy, Eugene J., 1968 (Box 13)
  - McCleery, William, 1964-1967; undated (Box 14)
    See also Ladies' Home Journal
  - McClintic, Guthrie, 1957 (Box 14)
  - McCord, David, 1945-1962 (Box 14)
  - McCormick, Ken, 1950-1969; undated (Box 14)
    See also Doubleday & Company
  - McCrudden, Francis Lambert, 1944 (Box 14)
  - McDonald, Donald, 1958-1964 (Box 14)
  - MacDowell Colony, 1953-1969 (Box 14)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1954-1966 (Box 14)
  - McHugh, Vincent, 1942 (Box 14)
  - McKinney, Laurence, 1941-1965; undated (Box 14)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Macmillan Company, 1946-1976; undated; 3 folders (Box 14)
  - [Sister Mary] Madeleva, 1935-1964; undated (Box 14)
  - Mademoiselle, 1953-1967; undated (Box 14)
  - Marks, Claude, 1957 (Box 14)
  - Marquand, John P., 1954 (Box 14)
  - Marquette University, 1958-1972; undated (Box 14)
  - Marx, Anne, 1963 (Box 14)
  - Marx, Groucho, 1953-1964 (Box 14)
  - Masters, Marcia Lee, 1967 (Box 14)
  - Maw, Margaret, 1951 (Box 14)
  - May, James Boyer, undated (Box 14)
  - Mayer, Ruth, 1968-1977; undated (Box 14)
  - Meacham, Harry M., 1961 (Box 14)
  - Mears, Alice Monks, 1959 (Box 14)
  - Mechem, Kirke, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Mehrtens, Ruth, 1965-1975; undated (Box 14)
  - Meneely, A. Howard, See Wheaton College
  - Menninger, Karl A., 1957; 1976 (Box 14)
  - Mills, Emma, 1937-1954; undated (Box 14)
  - Mitchell, Susanna Valentine, undated (Box 14)
  - Modell, Merriam and Walter, 1951-1977; undated (Box 14)
  - Moffett, Harriet, 1921-1960; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Moffett, Harriet, 1961-1964; undated; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Montagu, Ashley, 1960 (Box 15)
  - Moore, Douglas, 1965 (Box 15)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1962; undated (Box 15)
  - Moran, Mabel, 1952 (Box 15)
  - Morgan, Bayard Quincy, 1956; 1961 (Box 15)
  - Morgan, Mona, 1942 (Box 15)
  - Moreno, Zerka, 1966 (Box 15)
  - [William] Morrow & Company, Inc., 1952-1968 (Box 15)
  - Morton, David, 1943 (Box 15)
  - Moss, Frank E., 1968 (Box 15)
  - Motley, Red, 1957-1968; undated (Box 15)
  - Mowrer, Paul Scott, 1960-1961 (Box 15)
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1951-1963 (Box 15)
  - Museum of the City of New York, 1953-1954 (Box 15)
  - N, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Nash, Ogden, 1933; 1957,; undated (Box 15)
  - National Book Committee, Inc., 1955-1969 (Box 15)
  - National Conference of Christians & Jews, Inc., 1952-1969 (Box 15)
  - National Council of Catholic Men, 1958-1964; undated (Box 15)
  - National Council of Catholic Women, 1954-1966 (Box 15)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1955-1970; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1946-1961; undated (Box 16)
  - New York Public Library, 1944-1968; undated (Box 16)
  - New York State Select Committee to Review State's Abortion Law and Recommend Appropriate Changes (unofficial), 1968; correspondence, minutes, transcript of hearing (4 folders), report, clippings (Box 16)
  - The New York Times, 1942-1975; undated (Box 17)
  - The New Yorker, 1930-1977; undated (3 folders) (Box 17)
  - Newman, Mabel, 1955 (Box 17)
  - Nims, John Frederick, 1969 (Box 17)
  - [W. W.] Norton & Company, Inc., 1962 (Box 17)
  - Notestein, Wallace, 1943 (Box 17)
  - O, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - O'Conor, Norreys Jephson, 1953 (Box 17)
  - Olson, Esther E., 1928 (Box 17)
  - Olson, Sidney and Zembra, 1955-1975 (Box 17)
  - Open Court Publishing Company, 1968-1969; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - P, 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Packard, Vance, 1968 (Box 17)
  - Paladino, Lyn, 1962-1963 (Box 17)
  - Palffy, Eleanor, 1952 (Box 17)
  - Palmer Stuart, undated (Box 17)
  - Parker, Cornelia Stratton, 1954-1956; undated (Box 17)
  - Parker, James Reid, 1941-1953; undated (Box 17)
  - Parker, Maude, 1952; undated (Box 17)
  - P.E.N., 1951-1969 (Box 18)
  - Perkins, Anne, 1961-1963 (Box 18)
    See also Harper & Row
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1953-1962 (Box 18)
  - [Brother] Philip, 1953-1957 (Box 18)
  - Pier, Arthur Stanwood, 1954-1960; undated (Box 18)
  - Poetry Society of America, 1944-1976; undated (Box 18)
  - Prescott, Orville and Lilias, 1953-1976; undated; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Price, Garrett, 1961 (Box 18)
  - Pulitzer Prize, 1961-1975; undated (3 folders) (Box 18)
  - Purdue University, 1956-1963 (Box 18)
  - [G. P.] Putnam's Sons, 1956; 1964 (Box 18)
  - Q, 1 folder (Box 18)
  - R, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Rae, John, 1940 (Box 18)
  - Rampton, Calvin L., 1966; 1969 (Box 18)
  - Random House, 1957-1964 (Box 18)
  - The Reader's Digest, 1949-1977 (Box 18)
  - Rich, Gladys, 1940-1967 (Box 19)
    See also Writings: Lyrics
  - Ripperger, Helmut Lothar, 1941; undated (Box 19)
  - Ritter, Joseph, 1964 (Box 19)
  - Robb, Lynda Johnson, 1968 (Box 19)
  - Robinson, Gertrude, undated (Box 19)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A., See New York State Select Committee to Review State's Abortion Law and Recommend Appropriate Changes
  - Rodgers, Richard and Dorothy, 1964-1970; undated (Box 19)
  - Roosenburg, Henriette, undated (Box 19)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1937 (Box 19)
  - Root, Oren and Daphne, 1966-1974; undated (Box 19)
  - Rose, Elinor K., 1957 (Box 19)
  - Rosen, Herbert, 1955 (Box 19)
  - Ross, Nancy Wilson, 1962; 1964 (Box 19)
  - Ross, Orvis, 1952-1957 (Box 19)
  - Ross, Zola H., 1962 (Box 19)
  - Rosten, Norman, 1951; 1966,; undated (Box 19)
  - Royle, Josephine, 1966 (Box 19)
  - Russell, Sydney King, undated (Box 19)
  - Ryan, Cornelius and Kathryn, 1966-1974; undated (Box 19)
  - Ryan, Margaret, 1954-1962; undated (Box 19)
  - S, 9 folders (Box 19)
  - St. John, Adela Rogers, undated (Box 20)
  - St. John's University, 1960-1965 (Box 20)
  - The Saturday Evening Post, 1939-1968; undated (Box 20)
  - The Saturday Review, 1935-1964; undated (Box 20)
  - Schager, Edward, 1954-1976; undated (Box 20)
  - Scherman, Bernardine Kielty, 1959-1967; undated (Box 20)
  - [G.] Schirmer, Inc., 1927; 1956 (Box 20)
  - Schnirring, Alice Mary, 1954-1968; undated (Box 20)
  - Scholastic Magazines, 1946-1969 (Box 20)
  - Schubart, Mark, 1955 (Box 20)
  - Scott, Edgar, 1938-1951; undated (Box 20)
  - Scott, Foresman and Company, 1959-1965 (Box 20)
  - Sedgwick, R. Minturn, 1960-1966; undated (Box 20)
  - Seward, William W., 1954; 1958 (Box 20)
  - Sewell, Ruth, 1956-1968; undated (Box 20)
  - Sexton, Anne, 1963; 1966 (Box 20)
  - Shalit, Gene, 1968 (Box 20)
  - Shaw, John, 1954-1961 (Box 20)
  - Sheed & Ward, 1955-1962; undated (Box 20)
  - Shriver, Eunice Kennedy, 1968 (Box 20)
  - Shriver, Sargent, 1967-1968 (Box 20)
  - Shuster, George N. and Doris, 1952-1958 (Box 20)
  - The Sign, 1956-1966 (Box 20)
  - Silver, Burdett and Company, 1934-1954 (Box 20)
  - Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1960-1967 (Box 20)
  - Simpson, Louis, See Pulitzer Prize
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1962 (Box 20)
  - Skurzynski, Gloria, 1966-1977; undated (5 folders) (Box 20)
  - Slezak, Walter, 1959-1973; undated (Box 21)
  - Sloanaker, Hiram Lyday, undated (Box 21)
  - Smith College, 1961-1964 (Box 21)
  - Smythe, Daniel, 1967 (Box 21)
  - Spellman, Francis, 1962; 1964 (Box 21)
  - Spirit, See Brunini, John Gilland
  - Spiritual Life Institute of America, 1961-1963 (Box 21)
  - Staelin, Margaret Hudson, 1958-1960 (Box 21)
  - Stallman, Robert Wooster, 1948 (Box 21)
  - Stickney, Helen Frith, 1952 (Box 21)
  - Stiver, Mary Weeden, 1965 (Box 21)
  - Stout, Rex, 1952-1963 (Box 21)
  - Straus, Roger, 1953-1962 (Box 21)
  - Stringer, Arthur, 1944; undated (Box 21)
  - Stuart, Kenneth and Katharine, 1961-1977; undated (Box 21)
  - Sturdevant, John, 1942-1961; undated (Box 21)
  - Sullivan, Aloysius Michael, 1940-1970; undated (Box 21)
  - Sweeney, Francis, 1957-1976; undated (Box 21)
  - T, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Taggard, Genevieve, 1944; undated (Box 21)
  - Teichmann, Howard, 1961-1976 (Box 21)
  - Tenney, Edward Andrews, 1939; 1960 (Box 21)
  - Theta Phi Alpha, 1956-1968; undated (Box 21)
  - Theta Sigma Phi, 1951-1969; undated (Box 21)
  - This Week Magazine, 1960-1961 (Box 21)
  - Thompson, Dorothy Brown, 1961 (Box 21)
  - Thurston, Jarvis A., 1937 (Box 21)
  - Time, 1952-1975; undated (Box 21)
  - Tobin, James Edward, 1954 (Box 21)
  - Todd, Marjorie, 1947-1954; undated (Box 21)
  - Towne, Charles Hanson, 1939 (Box 21)
  - Trigere, Pauline, 1958 (Box 21)
  - Tucker, Irwin St. John, 1960-1967; undated (Box 21)
  - Turnbull, Agnes Sligh, 1960 (Box 21)
  - U, 1 folder (Box 21)
  - Udall, Stewart L., 1963; undated (Box 22)
  - Union Carbide Corporatio, 1968; undated (Box 22)
  - United States Information Agency, 1956-1966; undated (Box 22)
  - University of Notre Dame, 1963-1974 (Box 22)
  - University of Oregon, 1968 (Box 22)
  - University of Utah, 1957-1970 (Box 22)
  - University of Utah - Oversize material, 1930; 1961 (Oversize 1)
    University of Utah Teacher's High School Diploma, 1930
    University of Utah Teacher's Alumni Association Award, 1961
  - Untermeyer, Louis, 1938-1961; undated (Box 22)
  - Updike, John, 1958-1970 (Box 22)
  - Utah Writers' Conference, 1949-1950 (Box 22)
  - V, 1 folder (Box 22)
  - Vance, Eleanor Graham, 1967 (Box 22)
  - Van Dolah, Sheridan, 1951 (Box 22)
  - Van Doren, Mark, 1954; 1960 (Box 22)
  - Vanguard Press, 1939 (Box 22)
  - Van Hook, Lane, 1954 (Box 22)
  - Viereck, Peter, 1952; undated (Box 22)
  - Viking Press Inc., 1943-1975; undated; 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Vinal, Harold, See Voices: a Journal of Poetry
  - Vogue, 1957-1967 (Box 22)
  - Voices: a Journal of Poetry, 1930; 1933,; 1956,; 1962 (Box 22)
  - Von Trapp, Maria, 1973-1976; undated (Box 22)
  - W, 5 folders (Box 22)
  - Wade, Evelyn Amuedo, 1946; 1949 (Box 23)
  - Wagner, Linda W., 1966-1968 (Box 23)
  - Wagner, Linda W. - "Phyllis McGinley" - ms., 1968 (Box 23)
  - Wagner, Robert F., 1962 (Box 23)
  - Wagner-Martin, Linda, See Wagner, Linda W.
  - Walsh, Albert, undated (Box 23)
  - Walsh, Catherine, 1961 (Box 23)
  - Warbasse, Melba, 1942-1977; undated (Box 23)
  - Warner, Sylvia Townsend, 1958; 1960 (Box 23)
  - Washburn, Henry Bradford, 1960 (Box 23)
  - Wasson, Mildred, undated (Box 23)
  - [Franklin] Watts, Inc., 1959-1962 (Box 23)
  - Weihl, Elsa, 1960 (Box 23)
  - Weir, Ruth Cromer, 1945 (Box 23)
  - Wescott, Glenway, 1958-1967 (Box 23)
  - West, Morris L., 1965 (Box 23)
  - West, William W., 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Wheaton College, 1955-1965 (Box 23)
  - White, E. B., 1938-1948; 1973-1976,; undated (Box 23)
  - White, Helen C., 1957; 1964 (Box 23)
  - White, Katharine S., See The New Yorker; White, E. B.
  - White, Theodore H., 1961 (Box 23)
  - White House Festival of the Arts, 1965 (Box 23)
  - Whitehead, Jean, undated (Box 23)
  - Wickham, Anna, undated (Box 23)
  - Wickham, Florence, 1959 (Box 23)
  - Widdemer, Margaret, 1962-1968; undated (Box 23)
  - Wilder, Thornton, 1965; 1967,; undated (Box 23)
  - Williams, John A., 1962 (Box 23)
  - Wilson College, 1961-1964 (Box 23)
  - Woman's Day, 1967-1968 (Box 23)
  - Woman's Home Companion, 1952; 1956 (Box 23)
  - Wood, Audrey, 1948 (Box 23)
  - Woods, Ralph L., 1974 (Box 23)
  - Wouk, Herman, See Authors Guild
  - Wright, Ernest Hunter, 1952 (Box 23)
  - Wyatt, Jane, undated (Box 23)
  - X, 1 folder (Box 23)
  - Y, 1 folder (Box 23)
  - Yaddo, 1959 (Box 23)
  - Z, 1 folder (Box 23)
  - Unidentified, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Unidentified, 6 folders (Box 24)
  - Fan mail, 1928-1951; 6 folders (Box 24)
  - Fan mail, 1952-1960; 9 folders (Box 25)
  - Fan mail, 1961-1964; 9 folders (Box 26)
  - Fan mail, 1964-1965; 8 folders (Box 27)
  - Fan mail, 1965-1972; 8 folders (Box 28)
  - Fan mail, 1973-1978; undated; 9 folders (Box 29)
- Writings
  - Books
    - The B Book, manuscript; production records - printed, unbound (Box 30)
    - Blunderbus, manuscript; production records - dust jacket (Box 30)
    - A Girl and Her Room, work sheets (2 folders); manuscript (Box 30)
    - The Horse Who Had His Picture in the Paper, manuscript; production records - galley proofs (Box 30)
    - How Mrs. Santa Claus Saved Christmas, manuscript (Box 30)
    - The Love Letters of Phyllis McGinley, setting copy; production records - Table of Contents - galley proofs; production records - dust jacket (Box 30)
    - Lucy McLockett, manuscript; production records - galley proofs (Box 30)
    - The Make-Believe Twins, manuscript (Box 30)
    - Merry Christmas, Happy New Year, manuscript; manuscript (misc. pages) (Box 30)
    - Mince Pie and Mistletoe, manuscript; manuscript - jacket statement (Box 30)
    - The Most Wonderful Doll in the World, manuscript; production records - galley proofs (Box 30)
    - A Name for Kitty, manuscript (Box 30)
    - One More Manhattan, manuscript (Box 30)
    - The Plain Princess, setting copy; production records - galley proofs (Box 30)
    - A Pocketful of Wry, setting copy (2 folders) (Box 30)
    - The Province of the Heart, manuscript; etting copy (2 folders); production records - dust jacket (Box 31)
    - Saint-Watching, research material - notes and clippings; ms. drafts (5 folders); manuscript (2 folders); setting copy (4 folders) (Box 31)
    - Saint-Watching, production records - galley proofs; production records - dust jacket (Box 32)
    - A Short Walk from the Station (working title: "Suburbia, of Thee I Sing"), setting copy; production records - Table of Contents - galley proofs (Box 32)
    - Sixpence in Her Shoe, work sheets (6 folders) (Box 32)
    - Sixpence in Her Shoe, work sheets (2 folders); chapter: "A Wreath of Recipes" - manuscript; "A Note to English Readers" - manuscript; manuscript/setting copy (3 folders); production records - galley proofs (2 folders) (Box 33)
    - Sixpence in Her Shoe, production records - galley proofs (2 folders); production records - dust jacket (Box 34)
    - Sixpence in Her Shoe (Mexico, 1966) - La Casada "Perfecta" (Box 34)
    - Stones from a Glass House: New Poems, setting copy (Box 34)
    - Sugar and Spice: the ABC of Being a Girl, work sheets; manuscript (Box 34)
    - Times Three: Selected Verse from Three Decades, with Seventy New Poems, work sheets; manuscript; manuscript - "originally selected, marked for omission by MAB" (Box 34)
    - Times Three: Selected Verse from Three Decades, with Seventy New Poems, manuscript - "improbable inclusions"; manuscript - "possible inclusions"; deletions (last round); Foreword by W. H. Auden - manuscript; setting copy (7 folders); production records - Index of Titles and First Lines - galley proofs (Box 35)
    - Times Three: Selected Verse from Three Decades, with Seventy New Poems, production records - galley proofs; production records - dust jacket (Box 36)
    - Wonderful Time, work sheets; production records - folded and gathered sheets; production records - dust jacket (Box 36)
    - Wonders and Surprises, work sheets (4 folders); "rejects" (3 folders); "rejects" (2 folders) (Box 36)
    - Wonders and Surprises, manuscript (early) (2 folders); manuscript (2 folders); production records - galley proofs (4 folders); production records - dummy; production records - dust jacket (Box 37)
    - A Wreath of Christmas Legends, work sheets (2 folders); manuscript - final draft; manuscript (revision); production records - cover art; production records - facsimiles of sketches; production records - galley proofs (Box 38)
    - A Wreath of Christmas Legends, production records (Oversize 2)
    - The Year Without a Santa Claus, work sheets; manuscript; production records - galley proofs (Box 38)
  - Essays
    - "The Adventure of Getting Up in the Morning", manuscript (Box 38)
    - "Are Children People?" - Catholic Digest, May 1965 (Box 38)
    - "Are We Disillusioning Our Children?", manuscript (Box 38)
    - "Are Your Youngsters Dating Too Early?" - New York Journal-American, June 17, 1956 (Box 38)
    - "Ascent from Grandeur", ms. drafts, manuscript (Box 38)
    - "Ascent from Grandeur" - Annals of St. Anthony's Shrine, 1969 (Box 38)
    - "Beep, Beep" - America, Oct. 26, 1957 (Box 38)
    - "Books to Travel With", manuscript (Box 38)
    - "Carrousels! Spring!" - The New York Times Magazine, Mar. 29, 1953 (Box 38)
    - "A Cell of One's Own" (working title: "The First Feminists"), ms. drafts, manuscript (Box 38)
    - "The Changing of the Guard", ms. drafts, manuscript (Box 39)
    - "The Changing of the Guard" - Woman's Day, Sept. 1967 (Box 39)
    - "Christmas Shopping", manuscript (Box 39)
    - "The Consolations of Illiteracy" - The Saturday Review, 1953 (Box 39)
    - "Cooking to Me Is Poetry", manuscript (Box 39)
    - "Cooking to Me Is Poetry" - Ladies' Home Journal, Jan. 1960 (Box 39)
    - "Criminals at Large", manuscript (Box 39)
    - "A Culinary Garland", manuscript (Box 39)
    - "Do They Love You--Or Your Disguise?" (working title: "The Image of a Mother"), manuscript (Box 39)
    - "Do They Love You--Or Your Disguise?" - Glamour, May 1961 (Box 39)
    - "Drinking Etiquette for Ladies", manuscript (Box 39)
    - "The East Is Home" - Woman's Home Companion, July 1956 (Box 39)
    - "The Fearful Aspect of Too-Early Dating" - The Bulloch Herald,June 21, 1956 (Box 39)
    - "Flattery Can Get You Somewhere" (working title: "The True Bouquet"), ms. drafts, manuscript (Box 39)
    - "Flattery Can Get You Somewhere" - The Saturday Evening Post, Apr. 21, 1962 (Box 39)
    - "For Better, for Worse, But Not for Lunch" (working title: "But Not for Lunch"), ms. drafts (Box 39)
    - "For Better, for Worse, But Not for Lunch" - Ladies' Home Journal, Feb. 1965 (Box 39)
    - "For Mrs. Lenore Hershey of McCall's", manuscript (Box 39)
    - "Frankly Sentimental" - Harper's Magazine, Dec. 1950 (Box 39)
    - "Garden Addict Kicks the Habit" (working title: "The Education of a Gardener"), manuscript (Box 39)
    - "Garden Addict Kicks the Habit" - Life, May 12, 1958 (Box 39)
    - "A Garden Addict Kicks the Habit: Good-By, Green Thumb!" - The Reader's Digest, June 1959 (Box 39)
    - "A Garland of Envies", ms. draft; manuscript (Box 39)
    - "A Garland of Envies" - McCall's, Mar. 1961 (Box 39)
    - "A Garland of Kindness" - Suburbia Today, Dec. 1959 (Box 39)
    - "The Genuine Catholic School" - Catholic School Journal, Oct. 1969 (Box 39)
    - "Golden Journey", manuscript (Box 39)
    - "Good Companions", manuscript; ms., copyedited; production records - galley proofs (Box 39)
    - "The Good Life", ms. drafts (Box 39)
    - "Good Men and Beasts", ms. drafts (3 folders); manuscript (Box 39)
    - "Good Men and Beasts" - The Critic, Apr./May 1965 (Box 39)
    - "Guest of Dishonor", manuscript (Box 40)
    - "The Honor of Being a Woman" - The Reader's Digest, Dec. 1959 (Box 40)
    - "How Are Your Telephone Manners?", ms. Draft (Box 40)
    - "How I Plan to Vote in the Next Election", manuscript (Box 40)
    - "How to Get Along with a Man" - Vogue, Jan. 15, 1958 (Box 40)
    - "How to Torture a Writer Who Likes to Smoke" - The New York Times, Apr. 29, 1951 (Box 40)
    - "In Defence of Saint Paul", manuscript (Box 40)
    - "Incident on the Stamford Local", manuscript (Box 40)
    - "The Inconstant Reader, manuscript (Box 40)
    - "It's Really Hard Work Being Jolly in Suburbia" - Chicago Sunday Tribune, Dec. 2, 1951 (Box 40)
    - "The Jewel in the Pocket", ms. Drafts, manuscript (Box 40)
    - "Leave the Schools Alone", manuscript (Box 40)
    - "Let's Give Up Hate for Lent, manuscript (Box 40)
    - "Let's Give Up Hate for Lent" - The American Weekly, Mar. 3, 1957 (Box 40)
    - "The Light Side of the Moon", manuscript (Box 40)
    - "The Light Side of the Moon" - The American Scholar, autumn 1965; Ginn High School English Notes, fall 1965 (Box 40)
    - "A Little Grace" - Vogue, Jan. 15, 1961 (Box 40)
    - "Loafing: a Big Challenge to Men and a Laugh to Wives" - Life, Dec. 28, 1959 (Box 40)
    - "Machinery, Stay Away from My Door", manuscript (Box 40)
    - "Men Are What's Wrong with Kitchens", manuscript (Box 40)
    - "My Affair with a Hatrack" (working title: "The Battle of the Hat Rack"), manuscript (Box 40)
    - "The Myth of the Feminine", manuscript (Box 40)
    - "The Myths of Maternity", manuscript (Box 40)
    - "The New American Family", research material, ms. drafts, manuscript (Box 40)
    - "The New American Family" - The Saturday Evening Post, July 13, 1968 (Box 40)
    - "The Partly-Good Samaritans", manuscript (Box 40)
    - "Part-Time Poet" - Good Housekeeping, Dec. 1943 (Box 40)
    - "A Party for the Little Ones", manuscript (Box 40)
    - "Party Line" (working title: "Entertaining Without Tears"), ms. drafts (2 folders), ms. drafts (various pages) (Box 40)
    - "The Pastime Poets", production records - galley proofs (Box 40)
    - "Pipeline and Sinker" (working title: "Family Jokes"), manuscript (Box 40)
    - "Pipeline and Sinker" - Vogue, Aug. 1, 1958 (Box 40)
    - "Pleasant to Shop for, Pleasant to Give, and Always Easy to Wrap" (working title: "Books for Christmas"), manuscript (Box 40)
    - "Pleasant to Shop for, Pleasant to Give, and Always Easy to Wrap" - The New York Times Book Review, Nov. 30, 1958 (Box 40)
    - "The Pleasure of Being a Woman", manuscript (Box 40)
    - "The Pleasures of Picture Books" - Book News, Oct. 1949 (Box 40)
    - "A Poet on Poetry: It Must Attack the Senses and Pierce the Heart" - New York Herald Tribune, Dec. 27, 1953 (Box 40)
    - "Preparing for House Guests" - St. Louis Post-Dispatch,Jan. 17, 1965 (Box 40)
    - "Privacy/Noise" - House & Garden, Jan. 1957 (Box 40)
    - "Profession: Housewife"
      - "Profession: Housewife" - New York Journal-American Pictorial Living, Jan. 10, 1965 (Box 40)
      - "Profession: Housewife" - St. Louis Post-Dispatch, Jan. 10, 1965 (Box 40)
      - "Profession: Housewife: a Roof of One's Own" - Ladies' Home Journal, Oct. 1963 (Box 40)
      - "Profession: Housewife: a Self-Winding Plan to Keep Hubby Ulcer-Free, Long-Lived" - The Knickerbocker News, Jan. 12, 1965 (Box 40)
      - "Profession: Housewife: Are Children People?" - Ladies' Home Journal, June 1963 (Box 40)
      - "Profession: Housewife: Candid Thoughts on the Care and Feeding of Overnight Guests" - Ladies' Home Journal, July/Aug. 1963 (Box 40)
      - "Profession: Housewife: Decorating Your House--It Must Suit You" - St. Louis Post-Dispatch, Jan. 13, 1965 (Box 40)
      - "Profession: Housewife: Delicate Art of Getting Along with the Help" - St. Louis Post-Dispatch, Jan. 15, 1965 (Box 40)
      - "Profession: Housewife: Help!" - Ladies' Home Journal, Apr. 1963 (Box 41)
      - "Profession: Housewife: In One Era--and Out the Other" - Ladies' Home Journal, Apr. 1964 (Box 41)
      - "Profession: Housewife: Kitchens Are for Cooking" - Ladies' Home Journal, production records - galley proofs (Box 41)
      - "Profession: Housewife: Learning the Hard Facts of Home-Buying" - St. Louis Post-Dispatch, Jan. 12, 1965 (Box 41)
      - "Profession: Housewife: Party Line" - Ladies' Home Journal, Dec. 1962 (Box 41)
      - "Profession: Housewife: Pleasant Ordeal of Giving a Good Party" - St. Louis Post-Dispatch, Jan. 14, 1965 (Box 41)
      - "Profession: Housewife: Remodeling the Kitchen--An Unhappy Task" - St. Louis Post-Dispatch, Jan. 18, 1965 (Box 41)
      - "Profession: Housewife: the Myth of Grandmother's Cooking" - Ladies' Home Journal, Sept. 1962 (Box 41)
      - "Profession: Housewife: the Oldest Profession" - Ladies' Home Journal, summer 1962 (Box 41)
      - "Profession: Housewife: the Pleasures of Thrift" - Ladies' Home Journal, May 1963 (Box 41)
      - "Profession: Housewife: the Tools of the Trade" - Ladies' Home Journal, Mar. 1963 (Box 41)
      - "Profession: Housewife: Too Early Pressures on Today's Children" - St. Louis Post-Dispatch (Box 41)
      - "Profession: Housewife: What Cookbooks Don't Tell You" - Ladies' Home Journal, Nov. 1962 (Box 41)